SUMMARY

Highly adaptable analytics professional with 5 years of experience focusing on building custom analytics solutions. Well-versed in Python, R, and SQL, and always eager to learn more about underlying business processes in order to create meaningful solutions to business problems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst II - LTV Analytics Root Insurance Columbus OH Technology Used: SQL, R, Tableau, Mode Analytics, git

Oct 2021

- Current

• Provide analytics support for outside business requests on customer lifetime value related (LTV) metrics, and in the midst of designing a suite of executive-facing dashboards that provide insight into the validity and stability of our model produced LTV metrics.

Software Engineer - Data Science Engineering Root Insurance Columbus OH Mar 2020 Technology Used: Python, AWS, Docker, git, BuildKite, Terraform - Sept 2021

- Level I from Mar 2020 to Feb 2021, Level II from Feb 2021 to Sept 2021
- Provided continued support for the customer lifetime value prediction process, and helped create internal packages and templates for data scientists to use for easier machine learning model deployment in AWS SageMaker.
- Worked on developing SageMaker Endpoint APIs and serverless infrastructure to transition the scoring of users' telematics scores out of a Ruby on Rails app.

Senior Product Analyst - Mobile App Conversion Root Insurance Columbus OH Feb 2019

Technology Used: R, SQL, Python, AWS, Docker, git, Tableau

- Mar 2020

- Set up the initial daily customer lifetime value prediction process using AWS SageMaker, Lambda, and an internal data extraction tool. These results, while originally for the growth marketing team, became a staple in the company's overall decision making process.
- Led the analysis for several meaningful A/B tests in the mobile app experience, including: the efficacy of providing easy access to phone support during key points in the customer journey, and the improvement to several business metrics by allowing customer choice to affect their product experience.
- Worked to standardize the analysis of conversion A/B tests by creating an R package that provides analysts an abstraction for conducting a Bayesian analysis and produces a standardized report of the results.

Associate Data Scientist American Electric Power Columbus OH Technology Used: Python, R, Oracle, Linux, Docker, git

Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

• Created a daily statistical process for a quality control team that automated the prediction and cataloguing of potential errors in transmission data for 750 large commercial customers. Additionally, a dashboard created with Oracle APEX provided the team with a workflow to view and post notes about the predictions.

- Developed a data analysis tool and discrete-event simulation program that provided the ability to analyze the expected annualized costs for various predictive maintenance inspection regimens of the Amos power plant.
- Co-led an internal monthly meet-up around the uses of Python and R for analytics, where we typically had between 5 and 10 people each month.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mathematical Statistics, Minor in Economics Ohio University, Athens OH

Overall G.P.A: 3.82 / 4.00 Magna Cum Laude

Major G.P.A: 3.98 / 4.00 *Diploma Conferred on Dec 10th, 2016